Guide to the Charles M. Stein Papers SC1224
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Charles M. Stein papers
1945-2010
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stein, Charles
SC1224
48 Linear Feet (34 boxes)
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical / Historical
Charles M. Stein, professor emeritus of statistics, was one of the world’s premier mathematical statisticians.
Born in Brooklyn, New York in 1920, Stein had a natural talent for math from an early age. Stein earned his bachelor’s degree in mathematics at the University of Chicago in 1940, then worked for the U.S. Air Force during World War II. Alongside Kenneth Arrow, George Forsythe and Gil Hunt, he worked to verify weather broadcasts, critical for understanding how weather might affect wartime activities. Of his weather service work, Stein said in a 2003 interview published by Imprints, “Our participation in World War II was necessary in the fight against fascism […].” He spoke out against all United States involvement in wars since WWII and was often involved in anti-war protests.
After he was discharged from the Air Force in 1946, Stein completed his doctorate at Columbia University in 1947 and worked at the University of California, Berkeley, for the next two years, leaving because he refused to sign a loyalty oath, which resulted from McCarthy-era politics. This decision eventually brought him to Stanford, which, as a private university, required no such oath.
Stein was hired as an associate professor in 1953 but became a full professor just three years later. Although he retired in the late eighties, Stein continued to live close to Stanford for most of the rest of his life and stayed interested in his field. Partially motivated by a dream to use his namesake method (Stein’s method) to prove the prime number theorem (a mathematical statement about the distribution of prime numbers), he went to the library every day for an hour to read all the new math books.
Stein’s method, Stein’s lemma and Stein’s paradox are all named for him. Efron, along with his then-PhD student Carl Morris, wrote the 1977 Scientific American article that named Stein’s paradox, which came out of the James-Stein theorem (developed with Stein’s graduate student Willard James).
A basic summary of the paradox offered by Efron was “that there is unexpected information available if one has several independent estimates.” In the Scientific American article, Efron explained the paradox with a baseball example: while most people would think the best prediction for the end-of-season batting averages of 10 players would be obtained by looking at each player’s early average, the James-Stein theorem showed that including other players’ averages leads to a better result. This is a paradox because players’ individual performances shouldn’t influence each other.
Emmanuel Jean Candès, current chair of math and statistics, called the paradox, “the most provocative result in our field of mathematical statistics in our field in the last 60 years.” In addition to being highly practical and widely applicable, Candès said the paradox reminds statisticians, and scientists in general, that research is not only about validating your instincts, that there is a responsibility to do hard, trailblazing work as well.
Stein was renowned for his passionate social activism. He was opposed to war and refused to take military funding for his research. On Oct. 11, 1985, he was the first Stanford faculty arrested in apartheid protests, as reported by the Stanford Daily. His son, Charles Stein Jr., said that his father felt it was his responsibility to stand up for these causes. As a tenured professor, Stein Sr. believed he could use the privilege that came along with the security of his job to give voice to people who would suffer consequences for the same acts of protest.
Up until the last few years, Stein lived on campus. In addition to his daily library time, he came to seminars whenever possible. He hiked the Stanford hills every day and always led the way when out with the Loma Prieta chapter of the Sierra Club.
Stein was preceded in death by his wife, Margaret. He is survived by two daughters: Sara Stein, her husband, Gua-su Cui, and their son, Max Cui-Stein, of Arlington, Massachusetts; and Anne Stein and her husband, Ezequiel Pagan, of Peekskill, NY; and son Charles Stein Jr. and his wife, Laura Stoker, of Fremont, California.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Charles Stein, Jr., 2015.
Scope and Contents
Materials include professional and personal papers, technical reports, notebooks, and computer media.
Stanford University -- Faculty.; Universities and colleges -- Faculty.; Education -- Statistical methods; Mathematical statistics.; Statistics -- Study and teaching.; Stein, Charles; Stein, Charles
- Papers
  - Hans Samelson An Introduction to Linear Algebra, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Hypothese du Contesu, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Modern higher algebra, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 236c, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Time series, 1980 Jul (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Probability chapter 1, sections, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - notes on statistical decision thoery, 1964 Jun (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Sieve, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - approximation in probability, 1988 Jun (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - topics in probability, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Australian national university, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - II, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - general notes for course, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - unlabeled, 2000 Mar 26 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - notes for rewriting "approximate computation of expectations", 2004 Feb (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - unlabeled, 2003 Sep (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Stein, 2003 Fall (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Revision of "Approximate computation of expectations", 2002 Mar (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - unlabeled, 2000 Feb 28 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - unlabeled, 2003 Oct (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Special problems, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - PNT, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Statistics, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - PNT, 2005 Jun 13 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - some earlier fragments, 2005 Apr (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Statistics and Computing, 1993 Dec (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - unlabeled, 1999 May (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - normal approximation for sums of random variables, 2003 Nov (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - unlabeled, 1993 Aug (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Large-sample estimation, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Notes on the analysis of variance, 1955 Sep (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - notes on algebra for multivariate analysis, 1955 Sep (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Linear algebra, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - statistic decision theory, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - non-existence of an invariant minimax test, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - two body problem, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - miscellaneous, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - prediction of stationary normal processes continuity, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - information and comparison of experiments, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - transparencies, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - math notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - paper, 2000 Mar 28 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - math notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Shimodaira paper, 2000 Jan 27 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Shimodaira paper, 2000 Mar (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Employees' Association flier, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Letter to the editor, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Multivariate analysis topic II, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Admissibility of Pitman's estimator, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - correspondence, 1961 May 2 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - plan for research on the applications of group theory, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - publications of Charles Stein, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - multiple repression in the multivariable normal case, notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - multiple regression in the multivariable normal case, draft, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - topic III: examples of invariant measures, undated (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - topic III: examples of invariant measures, undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - statistics 246 lecture 4, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - statistics 246 lecture 4, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - prediction of an arbitrary sequence, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Leon Tolstoi booklet, undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - retirement annuity booklet, undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Anderson, undated (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Wishart distribution, undated (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Voks bulletin, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - math notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - current problems of mathematical statistics, undated (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Invariant measures and related topics, undated (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - a method of proving the asymptotic normality of certain random variables, undated (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - inadmissibility of the usual estimator for the mean of a multivariate normal distribution, undated (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - statistics 230c, undated (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - lectures on approximate computation of expextations, undated (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Welch + Peers, undated (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - IMS 59/60, undated (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Sieves, 1987 Oct (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - computing, undated (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - estimation of a covariance matrix, part 1, undated (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Wauaebckuri, undated (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Statistical problems invariant under a group of transformations, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - stat 269 papers, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - multivariate analysis ch. 1, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - proceedings of the third berkeley symposium, 1954-1955 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Karlan technical report no. 13, 1957 Apr 30 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - proceedings of the third berkeley symposium, 1954-1955 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - lecture notes, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Statistical problems invariant under a group of transformations, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - stat 269 papers, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - URY, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - multivariate analysis, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Admissibility for estimation with Quadratic Loss, 1957 Apr 30 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - a method of proving the asymptotic normality of certain random variables, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Global cross sections and invariante measures with applications to the densities of maximal invariants, 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - the number of successes in independent trials, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Berkeley lecture, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Approximate computation of probabilities and expectations, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - multinomial distributions, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - stein, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Poisson approximation, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Admissibility of Pitman's estimation for two local parameters, 1959 Feb 6 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - technical report no. 12, 1964 Jul 31 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - technical report no. 381, 1982 Jul (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Poisson Approximation II, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - An approach to the Approximate comp. of probabilities, 1981 Sep (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - random graphs, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - estimation of many parameters, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Confidence sets, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Guyon, Richardson, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Approximationd og Probabilities, undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Admissibility of estimates with quadratic loss, undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - lecture notes, undated (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Wald memorial lectures, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "Why do noninvertible estimated…., 1984 Oct (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Stat 151 notes 11-20, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - stat 236a, 1977 Autumn (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Stat 217, 1977 winter (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - stat 336A, 1977 Winter (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Stein stats 116, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - moving beyond myths National Research Council, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - From shuffling cards to walking around the building by Diaconis, 1998 Aug (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Prime number theory, 2001-2004 May (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - inadmissibility of the usual estimator for the mean of a multivariate normal distribution, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - approximation of improper prior measures by prior prob. Measures, 1964 Jul (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Multivariate analysis I technical report, 1969 Dec 2 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Multivariate analysis I technical report, 1969 Dec (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - A bound for the error in the normal approximation, 1970 Jun (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Leningrad lectures, 1976 Oct-Nov (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - An approach to the approximate computationof probabilities, 1981 Sep (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Asymptotic Evaluation of the number of Latin rectangles, 1978 Jul (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - correspondence, undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - on the Turan-Kubilius inequality, 1984 Jul (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - the number and regular graphs of given degree and order, 1989 Mar (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Application of Newton's identities to a generalized problem, 1990 Sep (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Admissibility of pitman's estimator of a single location parameter, 1959 Oct (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Example of the wide discrepency between fiducial + confidence intervals, 1959 Dec (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - multiple regression, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Estimation with a quadratic loss, 1960 Jun (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Estimation of Many parameters, 1961 Aug (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Conditional properties of confidence sets, in particular those associated with students t, 1962 Jun (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - unlabeled, undated (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Confidence sets for the mean of a multivariate normal distribution, 1962 Feb (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - A two-sample test for a linear hypothesis whose power in independent of the variance, 1945 Sep (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - a note on cumulative sums, 1946 Dec (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Sequential estimation, 1949 Jan (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - on the coverage probability of confidence sets based on a prior distribution, 1981 Nov (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - most powerful test of composite hypothesis - normal distribution, 1948 Dec (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - inadmissibility of the usual estimator for the mean of a multivariate normal distribution, 1955 Jul (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - A necessary and sufficient condition for admissibility, 1955 Sep (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Confidence sets for the mean of a multivariate normal distribution, undated (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Lecture V, undated (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Admissibility of certain invariant stat tests, 1955 Sep (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - a property of some tests of composite hypothesis, 1951 Sep (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - unlabeled, undated (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - jackknife estimate of variance, 1978 Oct (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - admissibility of the Bayes procedure corresponding to the uniform prior data, 1980 Jul (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Estimation of the mean of a multivariate normal distribution, 1981 Jan (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Concentration inequalities and the Berry-Essen theorem, undated (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - An approach to the recovery of inter block, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Decision theory, undated (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Computing, undated (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - Contains proof-reading near end, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - sequential analysis, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - random graphs, 1989 Jun (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - random graphs III Australian lectures, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - unlabeled, 1990 Jan (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Estimation of covariance matrix, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - estimation of a covariance matrix (outdated), undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - estimation of entropy, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - MS ACE, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - lecture I and II, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - lecture Vi, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Decision theory, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - lecture 3, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - lecture 2, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Lectures on statistical decision theory, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - miscellaneous, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Stein's method in a two-dimensional coverage problem, 1988 May (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - random graphs, 1989 Sep (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - lectures on Bivariate analysis preliminary version, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - better approximate confidence intervals in exponential families, 1990 Jun (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Technical report no. 37, 1985 Sep (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - technical report no. 38, 1985 Sep (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Fuchs, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - technical report no. 55, 1986 Feb (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - bootstrapping a regression equation, 1984 Mar (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - bootstrapping a regression equation, 1984 Mar (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Child care, undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - prop 13- effects, undated (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - likelihood principle, undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - On the consistency of Bayes' estimates, 1984 Feb (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - technical report no. 35, 1985 Aug (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - technical report no. 36, 1985 Aug (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Statistics and the scientific method, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - errors-in-variables regression using Stein estimates, 1986 Aug (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Approximations for errors in regression, 1986 Aug (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - regression models for adjusting the 1980 census, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - on energy policy methods, 1983 Jan (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Jerzy Neyman, 1988 May (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - EOC, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Prime numbers (CMS), undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Prime numbers (CMS), 1972 Nov (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - mostly decision theory, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Probability, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - probability, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Jordan canonical form, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Fragmentory notes on multivariable, etc, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - The Admissibility of Pitman's estimator for two location parameters technical report, 1959 Feb 6 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - statistics department, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Chapter 4: finite Gibbs and Markov states, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - convex functions (revised), undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - the approx normality of certain random valuable, undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Technical report, 1971 Jun 20 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - seminar on algebrain, 1949-1950 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - lecture 3, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Wald lecture 3, undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - 2nd Wald lecture, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Lectures on statistical decision theory, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - dissertation, 2002 Mar (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Normal approximation under local dependence, 2002 May 3 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - course evaluations, undated (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Stat 236A, undated (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - correspondence, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Chapter 2, 1988 Jun 13 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Poisson approximation, 1988 Jul 26 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Group representations and probability, 1964 Dec (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Estimators of a location parameter in the Absolutely continuous case, undated (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - technical reports, undated (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Cowles Commission Discussion paper, 1952 Sep 1 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Cowles Commission Discussion paper, undated (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - technical reports, undated (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Multivariate analysis, undated (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - multivariate analysis section II, undated (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - multivariate analysis section III, undated (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - multivariate analysis section IV, undated (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Technical report, 1959 Apr (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Lehmann paper, undated (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - technical reports, undated (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - technical reports, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - technical reports, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - paper, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - National Science Foundation, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Uzawa preference and rational choice in the theory of consumption, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - On Weak Convergence of Measures on [0,1], 1966 Feb (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Tucker on moments and normalizing coefficients, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Technical Report, 1962 Nov (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Central limit theory, undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Estimation of Two ordered translation parameters, undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Bayesian statistics, undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - first draft of Bibiography, undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Otto Hans on rnadom Operator Equations, undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Contributors to the Theory of Random Mappings, undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Edwin Hewitt Fourier Transforms of the Class Lp, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Brillinger some Aspects of Statistical Invariance, undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Burkholder, undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Bhapkar Contributions to Statistical Analysis, 1959 Jul (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Mikhail Multivariate Analysis, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Orey potential Kernals for recurrent Markov chains, undated (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Linnik on the Probability of Large Deivations for the sums of independent variables, undated (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - notes on Least Squares Roy, 1953 Aug (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Feldman Equivalence and Perpendicularity of Gaussian processes, undated (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Strassen A Converse to the Law of the Iterated Logarithm, undated (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Strassen the Existence of Probability Measures with Given Marginals, undated (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Gastwirth, 1964 Dec (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Yosida on a Class of Infinitesimal Generators…, undated (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Estimation of Many Parameters II, 1980 Jun (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Approximations of Probabilities II, undated (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - A conversation with Charles Stein, undated (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Estimation of Many Parameters II, 1980 Winter (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Statistics 236, 1987 Fall (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Statistics 332, undated (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - on the multistage model for carcinogens, 1988 May 1 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - technical report no. 21, 1989 Jul (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - storage, undated (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Soren TolverJensen Covariance Hypotheses which are linear, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Technical report, 1989 Mar (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - A Normal Approximationfor the number of local maxima, 1998 Nov (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Rate of Poisson Convergence in Equiprobable Allocations, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - the Differential Inequality of a Statistical Estimation, 1981 Jan (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Minimax Risk over Lp - balls, 1989 Apr 29 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Poisson approximation, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Department of Mathematics, 1989 May (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Technical Report, 1988 Aug (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - European Meeting of Statisticians, 1988 Aug 22-26 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Proceedings of the sixth Berkeley symposium on Mathematical Statistics and Probability, undated (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Approximations in Probability, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Probability I, undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - normal approximations for sums, 2001 May 20 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - unlabeled, 2001 Oct 24 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - unlabeled, 2003 Feb (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - unlabeled, 2000 Sep (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - unlabeled, 1999 Aug (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - unlabeled, 1989 Dec (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - unlabeled, 2003 Jun 17 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - plans for lecture notes, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - random events, undated (Box 23, Folder 22)